synthesio.com 2019-11-01

# Privacy Policy | Synthesio

Skip to content

Privacy Policy[Chris Vitti](https://www.synthesio.com/author/cvitti/ "Posts by Chris Vitti")2019-10-31T10:13:58-04:00

Synthesio Privacy Policy

Last updated: 9 May 2018

Synthesio respects your privacy and is committed to protecting your personal data. This website privacy policy will inform you as to how we look after your personal data when you visit our website and tell you about your privacy rights and how the law protects you.

This website privacy policy is provided in a layered format so you can click through to the specific areas set out below. Alternatively, you can download a PDF version of the policy within your browser by going to Print > Save as PDF. Please also use the Glossary to understand the meaning of some of the terms used in this website privacy policy.

  1. Purpose Of This Privacy Policy
  2. The Data We Collect
  3. How Personal Data Is Collected
  4. What Cookies We Use And For What Purposes
  5. How We Use Your Personal Data
  6. Disclosures Of Your Personal Data
  7. International Transfers
  8. Data Security
  9. Data Retention
  10. Accessing, Correcting And Deleting Your Information
  11. Changes To The Privacy Policy And Your Duty To Inform Us Of Changes
  12. Glossary

This website privacy policy aims to give you information on how Synthesio collects and processes your personal data through your use of this website, including any data you may provide through this website when you sign up to our newsletter, watch one of our webinar recordings, send us a demo request, register and log into our application, contact us through our Contact form or Demo form.

This website is not intended for children under 16 years of age. No one under age 16 may provide any information to or on this website. We do not knowingly collect personal information from children under 16. If you are under 16, do not use or provide any information on this website or on or through any of its features/register on the website, use any of the interactive or public comment features of this website or provide any information about yourself to us, including your name, address, telephone number, email address, or any screen name or user name you may use. If we learn we have collected or received personal information from a child under 16 without verification of parental consent, we will delete that information. If you believe we might have any information from or about a child under 16, please contact us.

It is important that you read this website privacy policy together with any other privacy notice or fair processing notice we may provide on specific occasions when we are collecting or processing personal data about you, so you are fully aware of how and why we are using your data. This website privacy notice supplements the other policies and notices and is not intended to override them.

## Controller

Synthesio is made up of different legal entities, details of which can be found here. This website privacy policy is issued on behalf of the Synthesio Group so when we mention “Synthesio”, “we”, “us” or “our” in this website privacy policy, we are referring to the relevant company in the Synthesio Group responsible for processing your data. If you are based in the European Union, we will let you know which entity will be the controller for your data when you purchase a service with us.

If you are based in the **United States** , Synthesio, Inc. is the data controller and responsible for this website.

If you are based in **Singapore** , Synthesio Pte is the data controller and responsible for this website.

If you are based in the **U.K.** , Synthesio LTD is the data controller and responsible for this website.

If you are based in **France** , Synthesio SAS is the data controller and responsible for this website.

If you are based in **Belgium** , Social Karma SA is the data controller and responsible for this website.

We have appointed a data protection officer (DPO) who is responsible for overseeing questions about this website privacy policy. If you have any questions about this website privacy notice, including any requests to exercise your legal rights, please contact the DPO using the details set out below.

Please submit any questions, concerns or comments you have about this website privacy policy or any requests concerning your personal data by email to privacy at synthesio dot com

Our full details are:

Synthesio

Julien Plée, Data Protection Officer

Email address: privacy at synthesio dot com

Postal address: 8/10 rue Villedo, 75001 Paris, FRANCE

Telephone number: +33 1 44 77 89 10

If you are based in the European Union you have the right to make a complaint at any time to your local supervisory authority for data protection issues. The information about your supervisory authority can be found below:

If you are based in the UK: the Information Commissioner’s Office (ICO) at [www.ico.org.uk](http://www.ico.org.uk/)

If you are based in France: the Commission Nationale de l’Informatique et des Libertés (CNIL) at [https://www.cnil.fr/en/contact-cnil](https://www.cnil.fr/en/contact-cnil)

If you are based in Belgium: the Belgian Data Protection Authority at [commission@privacycommission.be](mailto:commission@privacycommission.be)

We would, however, appreciate the chance to deal with your concerns before you approach your local supervisory authority, so please contact us first.

Personal data, or personal information, means any information about an individual from which that person can be identified. It does not include data where the identity has been removed (anonymous data).

We may collect, use, store and transfer the following personal information about you:

  * **Identity Data** , which includes your first and last name
  * **Contact Data** , which includes your work email and postal address, your telephone number, your company name and your country location
  * **Technical Data** , which includes your internet protocol (IP) address, your login data, your browser type and version, time zone setting and location, browser plug-in types and versions, operating system and platform and other technology on the devices you use to accept this website
  * **Profile Data** , which includes your username and password, purchases or orders made by you.
  * **Usage Data** , which includes information about how you use our website, products, and services
  * **Marketing and Communications Data** , which includes your preferences in receiving marketing from us and our third parties and your communication preferences

We also collect, use and share **Aggregated Data** , such as statistical or demographic data for any purpose. Aggregated Data may be derived from your personal data but is not considered personal data in law as this data does not directly or indirectly reveal your identity. For example, we may aggregate your Usage Data to calculate the percentage of users accessing a specific website feature. However, if we combine or connect Aggregated Data with your personal data so that it can directly or indirectly identify you, we treat the combined data as personal data which will be used in accordance with this website privacy policy.

You are under no obligation to provide any such information, however, where we need to collect personal data by law, or under the terms of a contract we have with you and you fail to provide that data when requested, we may not be able to perform the contract we have or are trying to enter with you. In this case, we may have to cancel a product or service you have with us but we will notify you if this is the case at the time.

If you access this website from the European Union please note that we do not collect any **Special Categories of Data** about you (this includes details about your race or ethnicity, religious or philosophical beliefs, sex life, sexual orientation, political opinions, trade union membership, information about your health and genetic and biometric data). Nor do we collect any information about criminal convictions and offenses.

We use different methods to collect data from and about you including through:

  * **Direct interactions.** You may give us your Identity, Contact Data by filling in forms or by corresponding with us by post, phone, email or otherwise. This includes personal data you provide when you:
    * Apply for our products or services
    * Create an account on our web application
    * Log into our web application
    * Subscribe to our newsletter
    * Request to watch one of our on-demand webinars
    * Send us a demo request
    * Request marketing to be sent to you
    * Contact us through our Contact Us form
    * Give us some feedback

  * **Automated technologies or interactions.** As you interact with our website, we may automatically collect Technical Data about your equipment, browsing actions and patterns. We collect this personal data by using cookies, server logs, and other similar technologies. For more information about our cookies, please click here.
  * **Third parties or publicly available sources.** We may receive personal data about you from various third parties and public sources as set out below:
  * Technical Data from the following parties:

  * Analytics providers such as Google based outside the EU
  * Geolocation providers such as Nominatim, based outside the EU

  * Identity, Profile, and Usage Data from publicly available sources, such as social networking platforms based outside the EU.

Should you wish to obtain any specific information about the third parties from which we may receive personal data about you, please contact us.

Where you use third-party social networking sites, the third-party social networking site controls the information it collects from you. For information about how they may use and disclose your information, including any information you make public, please consult those third-party networking sites’ respective privacy policies.

Our website uses cookies or similar technologies to collect information about your access to the website. This helps us to provide you with a good experience when you browse our website and allows to improve our site.

Cookies are small pieces of information that include a unique reference code that a website places on a computer used to access the Internet that can be used to recognize a return visitor and enable the collection and storage information about your activity on our website. Many cookies we use last only for the duration of your web session and expire when you close your browser. Other cookies are used to remember you when you return to the website and will last for a longer period.

We use the following cookies:

**Strictly necessary cookies.** These are cookies that are required for the operation of our website. They include, for example, cookies that enable you to log into secure areas of our website.

**Analytical/performance** **cookies** **.** They allow us to recognize and count the number of visitors and to see how visitors move around our website when they are using it. This helps us to improve the way our website works, for example, by ensuring that users are finding what they are looking for easily.

**Functionality** **cookies** **.** These are used to recognize you when you return to our website. This enables us to personalize our content for you, greet you by name and remember your preferences (for example, your choice of language or region).

**Targeting** **cookies** **.** These cookies record your visit to our website, the pages you have visited and the links you have followed. We will use this information to make our website and the advertising displayed on it more relevant to your interests. We may also share this information with third parties for this purpose.

You can find more information about the individual cookies we use and the purposes for which we use them in the table below:

**Cookie Name** | **Owner** | **Expires** | **Note**  
---|---|---|---  
qtrans_cookie_test | Synthesio Blog | When you close your browser | Used for detecting if your browser supports cookies and if you accept them  
_ga | Google Analytics | 2 years | Used to distinguish users. More info on this page https://developers.google.com/analytics/devguides/collection/analyticsjs/cookie-usage[SG12]   
__utmz | Google Analytics | 6 months from set/update | Stores the traffic source or campaign that explains how the user reached your site. The cookie is created when the javascript library executes and is updated every time data is sent to Google Analytics. More info on this page https://developers.google.com/analytics/devguides/collection/analyticsjs/cookie-usage[SG13]   
__utmc | Google Analytics | When you close your browser | Historically, this cookie operated in conjunction with the __utmb cookie to determine whether the user was in a new session/visit. More info on this page https://developers.google.com/analytics/devguides/collection/analyticsjs/cookie-usage[SG14]   
__utma | Google Analytics | 2 years from set/update | Used to distinguish users and sessions. More info on this page https://developers.google.com/analytics/devguides/collection/analyticsjs/cookie-usage[SG15]   
__utmb | Google Analytics | 30 mins from set/update | Used to determine new sessions/visits. More info on this page [https://developers.google.com/analytics/devguides/collection/analyticsjs/cookie-usage](https://developers.google.com/analytics/devguides/collection/analyticsjs/cookie-usage)  
_mkto_trk | Marketo email tracking[SG17]  | When you close your browser | Marketo tracking cookies allow us to collect information about how you use our site after you have received an email from us. The cookies track data linked to your email address and include data such as how you arrived at the site, how often you’ve visited, and which pages you looked at.  
PHPSESSID | Synthesio tools | When you close your browser | Used to distinguish users  
synthCookieCheck | Synthesio tools | When you close your browser | Used for detecting if your browser supports cookies and if you accept them  
  
Some of the cookies used on our website are set by us, and some are set by third parties who are delivering services on our behalf.

Please note that third parties (including, for example, advertising networks and providers of external services like web traffic analysis services) may also use cookies, over which we have no control. These cookies are likely to be analytical/performance cookies or targeting cookies.

## Managing, Blocking and Deleting Cookies

Some Internet browsers contain controls for managing cookies. Those controls may enable you to delete cookies or to accept or reject certain categories of cookies. You may be able to manage other (non-cookie) tracking technologies through the websites of the firms that provide such technologies or through the operating system of your mobile device. You should consult the “Help” section of your browser or the website of your hardware, software, or operating system providers for further information. You can also learn more about cookies by visiting [allaboutcookies.org](http://www.allaboutcookies.org/), which includes additional useful information on cookies and how to block cookies using different types of browsers.

Please note that if you reject or delete cookies the related features and functions of our website may be unavailable to you and the performance of our website as experienced by you may be impaired.

We will use the personal data you provide to us in the following circumstances:

  * Where we need to perform the contract we are about to enter into or have entered into with you
  * Where it is necessary for our legitimate interests (or those of a third party) and, if you are based in the European Union, your interests and fundamental rights do not override those interests
  * Where we need to comply with a legal or regulatory obligation

Generally, we do not rely on consent as a legal basis for processing your personal data other than in relation to sending third-party direct marketing communications to you via email or text message. You have the right to withdraw consent to marketing at any time by clicking the “unsubscribe” link at the bottom of all emails.

## Purposes For Which We Will Use Your Personal Data

We have set out below, in a table format, a description of all the ways we plan to use your personal data, and which of the legal basis we rely on to do so. We have also identified what our legitimate interests are where appropriate.

Note that we may process your personal data for more than one lawful ground depending on the specific purpose for which we are using your data. Please contact us if you need details about the specific legal ground we are relying on to process your personal data where more than one ground has been set out in the table below.

**Purpose/Activity** | **Type of data** | **The lawful basis for processing including the basis of legitimate interest**  
---|---|---  
To register you as a new customer | (a) Identity

(b) Contact

| Performance of a contract with you  
To manage our relationship with you which will include notifying you about changes to our terms or privacy policy | (a) Identity

(b) Contact

(c) Profile

(d) Marketing and Communications

| (a) Performance of a contract with you

(b) Necessary to comply with a legal obligation

(c) Necessary for our legitimate interests (to keep our records updated and to study how customers use our products/services)  
  
To administer and protect our business and this website (including troubleshooting, data analysis, testing, system maintenance, support, reporting and hosting of data)  | (a) Identity

(b) Contact

(c) Technical

| (a) Necessary for our legitimate interests (for running our business, provision of administration and IT services, network security, to prevent fraud and in the context of a business reorganization or group restructuring exercise)

(b) Necessary to comply with a legal obligation  
  
To deliver relevant website content and advertisements to you and measure or understand the effectiveness of the advertising we serve to you | (a) Identity

(b) Contact

(c) Profile

(d) Usage

(e) Marketing and Communications

(f) Technical

| Necessary for our legitimate interests (to study how customers use our products/services, to develop them, to grow our business and to inform our marketing strategy)  
To use data analytics to improve our website, services, marketing, customer relationships and experiences | (a) Technical

(b) Usage

| Necessary for our legitimate interests (to define types of customers for our services, to keep our website updated and relevant, to develop our business and to inform our marketing strategy)  
To make suggestions and recommendations to you about services that may be of interest to you | (a) Identity

(b) Contact

(c) Technical

(d) Usage

(e) Profile

| Necessary for our legitimate interests (to develop our products/services and grow our business)  
To provide our services to customers | (a) Identity

(b) Profile

(c) Usage

(d) Marketing and Communications

| Necessary for our legitimate interests (to provide our core services to customers, e.g., social media listening, data analytics, analysis of brand perception and reputation in the online space, and analysis and perception of customers’ products online).  
  
## Marketing

We strive to provide you with choices regarding certain personal data uses, particularly in marketing and advertising.

### Promotional Offers From Us

We may use your Identity, Contact, Technical, Usage and Profile Data to form a view on what we think you may want or need, or what may be of interest to you. This is how we decide which products, services, and offers may be relevant to you.

You will receive marketing communications from us if you have requested information from us or purchased products or services and, in each case, you have not opted out of receiving that marketing.

### Third-Party Marketing

We will get your express opt-in consent before we share your personal data with any company outside the Synthesio group of companies for marketing purposes.

### Opting Out

You can ask us or third parties to stop sending you marketing messages at any time by clicking the “unsubscribe” link at the bottom of any email.

Where you opt out of receiving these marketing messages, this will not apply to personal data provided to us because of a service purchase or service experience.

We may have to share your personal information with the parties set out below for the purposes set out in the table in paragraph 5 above:

  * Internal Third Parties as set out in the Glossary
  * External Third Parties as set out in the Glossary
  * Third parties to whom we may choose to sell, transfer, or merge parts of our business or our assets. Alternatively, we may seek to acquire other businesses or merge with them. If a change happens to our business, then the new owners may use your personal data in the same way as set out in this website privacy policy

We require all third parties to respect the security of your personal data and to treat it in accordance with the law. We do not allow our third-party service providers to use your personal data for their own purposes and only permit them to process your personal data for specified purposes and in accordance with our instructions.

If you access our website from the European Union, please note that we share your personal data in the Synthesio Group. This will involve transferring your data outside the European Economic Area (“EEA”).

Many of our external third parties are based outside the EEA so their processing of your personal data will also involve a transfer of data outside the EEA.

Whenever we transfer your personal data out of the EEA, we ensure a similar degree of protection is afforded to it by ensuring that we use specific contracts approved by the European Commission which give personal data the same protection it has in Europe. For further details, see [European Commission](https://ec.europa.eu/info/law/law-topic/data-protection/data-transfers-outside-eu/model-contracts-transfer-personal-data-third-countries_en): Model contracts for the transfer of personal data to third countries.

Where we use providers based in the U.S., we may transfer data to them if they are part of the Privacy Shield which requires them to provide similar protection to personal data shared between Europe and the U.S. For further details, see [European Commission: EU-US Privacy Shield](https://ec.europa.eu/info/law/law-topic/data-protection/data-transfers-outside-eu/eu-us-privacy-shield_en).

Please contact us if you want further information on the specific mechanism used by us when transferring your personal data out of the EEA.

Synthesio places great importance on the security of all personal data associated with our website users. We have appropriate security measures in place to protect against the loss, misuse, and alteration of personal information under our control. Our security and privacy policies are periodically reviewed and enhanced as necessary and only authorized personnel have access to personal information. Whilst we cannot ensure or guarantee that loss, misuse or alteration of information will never occur, we use all reasonable efforts to prevent it.

Unfortunately, the transmission of information via the internet is not completely secure. Although we will do our best to protect your personal data, we cannot guarantee the security of your data transmitted to our site; any transmission is at your own risk. Once we have received your information, we will use strict procedures and security features to try to prevent unauthorized access.

We have also put in place procedures to deal with any suspected personal data breach and will notify you and any applicable regulator of a breach where we are legally required to do so.

We will only retain your personal data for if necessary to fulfill the purposes we collected it for, including for the purposes of satisfying any legal, accounting, or reporting requirements.

To determine the appropriate retention period for personal data, we consider the amount, nature, and sensitivity of the personal data, the potential risk of harm from unauthorised use or disclosure of your personal data, the purposes for which we process your personal data and whether we can achieve those purposes through other means, and the applicable legal requirements.

Details of retention periods for different aspects of your personal data are available in our retention policy which you can request from us by contacting us.

**US residents** : You have the right to request access to your personal data or to request that your personal data be rectified, or updated. You may also object to the processing of your personal data by us for legitimate reasons. If you feel that we process personal data relating to you and should you wish to exercise your rights, please contact us at the following address: 

Synthesio, Inc.

35 West 31 Street, 5th floor 

New York, NY 10001

California Privacy Rights: Under California Civil Code sections 1798.83-1798.84, California residents are entitled to ask us for a notice identifying the categories of personal customer information which we share with our affiliates and/or third parties for marketing purposes, and providing contact information for such affiliates and/or third parties. If you are a California resident and would like a copy of this notice, please submit a written request to the following address: Synthesio, 35 West 31 Street, 5th floor, New York, NY 10001.

**EU residents** : under certain circumstances, you have rights under data protection laws in relation to your personal data. Please click on the links below to find out more about these legal rights:

  * Request access to your personal data
  * Request correction of your personal data
  * Request erasure of your personal data
  * Object to the processing of your personal data
  * Request restriction of processing your personal data
  * Request transfer of your personal data
  * Right to withdraw consent

If you wish to exercise any of the rights set out above, please contact us.

## No Fee Usually Required

You will not have to pay a fee to access your personal data (or to exercise any of the other rights). However, we may charge a reasonable fee if your request is clearly unfounded, repetitive or excessive. Alternatively, we may refuse to comply with your request in these circumstances.

## What We May Need From You

We may need to request specific information from you to help us confirm your identity and ensure your right to access your personal data (or to exercise any of your other rights). This is a security measure to ensure that personal data is not disclosed to any person who has no right to receive it. We may also contact you to ask you for further information in relation to your request to speed up our response.

## Time Limit To Respond

We try to respond to all legitimate requests within one month. Occasionally it may take us longer than a month if your request is particularly complex or you have made several requests. In this case, we will notify you and keep you updated.

## External Links

This website may, from time to time, include links to third-party websites, plugins, and applications. Clicking on those links or enabling those connections may allow third parties to collect or share data about you. We do not control these third-party websites and are not responsible for their privacy statements. When you leave our website, we encourage you to read the privacy policy of every website you visit.

Synthesio may amend this website privacy policy from time to time. Synthesio will provide notification of the material changes to this Website Privacy Policy by way of a pop-up notice on Synthesio’s website at least thirty (30) business days prior to the change taking effect.  The date this website privacy policy was last revised is identified at the top of the page. You are responsible for periodically visiting our website and this website privacy policy to check for any changes.

It is important that the personal data we hold about you is accurate and current. Please keep us informed if your personal data changes during your relationship with us.

## EU Lawful Basis

**Legitimate Interest** means the interest of our business in conducting and managing our business to enable us to give you the best service/product and the best and most secure experience. We make sure we consider and balance any potential impact on you (both positive and negative) and your rights before we process your personal data for our legitimate interests. We do not use your personal data for activities where our interests are overridden by the impact on you (unless we have your consent or are otherwise required or permitted to by law). You can obtain further information about how we assess our legitimate interests against any potential impact on you in respect of specific activities by contacting us.

**Performance of Contract** means processing your data where it is necessary for the performance of a contract to which you are a party or to take steps at your request before entering such a contract.

**Comply with a legal or regulatory obligation** means processing your personal data where it is necessary for compliance with a legal or regulatory obligation that we are subject to.

## Third Parties

### Internal Third Parties

Other companies in the Synthesio Group acting as joint controllers or processors and who are based in the United States, the UK, Belgium and Singapore, and provide software setup, IT system administration, and client account management services.

### External Third Parties

  * Service providers acting as processors based in France and the United States who provide IT and system administration services, analytics services
  * Professional advisers acting as processors or joint controllers including lawyers, bankers, and auditors based in France, the United Kingdom, Singapore, and the United States, who provide consultancy, banking, legal, and accounting services
  * Regulators and other authorities acting as processors or joint controllers based in the UK, France, Belgium, the United States, and Singapore, who require reporting of processing activities in certain circumstances

### EU residents: If you wish to receive specific information about external third parties with which we may be sharing your personal data, please feel free to contact us.

### EU Residents: Your Legal Rights

If you are accessing this website from the European Union, please note that under EU data protection laws you have the right to:

#### Request Access To Your Personal Data

Request access to your personal data (commonly known as a “data subject access request”). This enables you to receive a copy of the personal data we hold about you and to check that we are lawfully processing it.

#### Request Correction Of Your Personal Data

Request correction of the personal data that we hold about you. This enables you to have any incomplete or inaccurate data we hold about you corrected, though we may need to verify the accuracy of the new data you provide to us.

#### Request Erasure Of Your Personal Data

Request erasure of your personal data. This enables you to ask us to delete or remove personal data where there is no good reason for us continuing to process it. You also have the right to ask us to delete or remove your personal data where you have successfully exercised your right to object to processing (see below), where we may have processed your information unlawfully or where we are required to erase your personal data to comply with local law. Note, however, that we may not always be able to comply with your request of erasure for specific legal reasons which will be notified to you, if applicable, at the time of your request.

#### Object To The Processing Of Your Personal Data

Object to the processing of your personal data where we are relying on a legitimate interest (or those of a third party), and there is something about your situation which makes you want to object to processing on this ground as you feel it impacts on your fundamental rights and freedoms. You also have the right to object where we are processing your personal data for direct marketing purposes. In some cases, we may demonstrate that we have compelling legitimate grounds to process your information which override your rights and freedoms.

#### Request Restriction Of Processing Your Personal Data

Request restriction of processing of your personal data. This enables you to ask us to suspend the processing of your personal data in the following scenarios: (a) if you want us to establish the data’s accuracy; (b) where our use of the data is unlawful, but you do not want us to erase it; (c) where you need us to hold the data even if we no longer require it as you need it to establish, exercise or defend legal claims; or (d) you have objected to our use of your data but we need to verify whether we have overriding legitimate grounds to use it.

#### Request Transfer Of Your Personal Data

Request the transfer of your personal data to you or a third party. We will provide you, or a third party you have chosen, your personal data in a structured, commonly used, machine-readable format. Note that this right only applies to automated information which you initially provided consent for us to use or where we used the information to perform a contract with you.

#### Right To Withdraw Consent

Withdraw consent at any time where we are relying on consent to process your personal data. However, this will not affect the lawfulness of any processing carried out before you withdraw your consent. If you withdraw your consent, we may not be able to provide specific products or services to you. We will advise you if this is the case at the time you withdraw your consent.
